<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="types_of_ds"><b>TYPES OF DATA STRUCTURES</b></string>

    <string name="description">Programming languages has a variety of data structures. In this section, we will just introduce them. We will discuss
        them in detail in Explores section. </string>

<!--    arrays-->
    <string name="array">🟣 <b>ARRAYS</b></string>
    <string name="arrays_description">An array is a collection of similar data elements. These data elements have the same data type. The elements of the array
    are stored in consecutive memory locations and are referenced by an index (also known sa the subscript).</string>
    <string name="array_declaration">Arrays are declared using the following syntax.\n    type name[size]; ....(in C language) \n For example, \n    int marks[10]</string>
    <string name="array_explain">The above statement declares an array marks that contains 10 elements. The array index starts from zero. This means that the array
    marks will contain 10 elements in all. The first element will be stored in marks[0], second element in marks[1], so on and so forth.</string>

<!--      stacks-->
    <string name="stack">🟣 <b>STACKS</b></string>
    <string name="stack_description">In the computers memory, stacks can be represented as a linear array. Every stack has a variable TOP associate with it. TOP is
    used to store  the address of the topmost element of the stack. It is this position from where the element will be added or deleted. There is another variable
    MAX, which will be used to store the maximum number of elements that the stack can store. \n    If TOP = NULL, then it indicates that hte stack is empty and
        if Top = MAX, then the stack is full.</string>

<!--    queue-->
    <string name="queue">🟣 <b>QUEUE</b></string>
    <string name="queue_description">A queue is a FIFO (First-In First-Out) data structure in which the element that wa inserted first is the first one to be
        taken out. The elements in a queue are added at one end called the rear and removed from the other end called the front. Like stacks, queues can be
    implemented either by using arrays or linked lists. \n \t Every queue will have front and rear variable that will point to the position from where
        deletions and insertions can be done, respectively. Consider a queue given below.</string>

<!--    Linkedlist-->
    <string name="linklist">🟣 <b>LINKED LIST</b></string>
    <string name="linklist_description">Linked list is a very flexible, dynamic data structure in which the elements can be added to or deleted from anywhere at will.
         In contrast to using static arrays, a programmer need not worry about how many elements will be stored in the linked list. This feature  enables the programmers
         to write robust programs which require less maintenance. \n \t In a linked list, each element (is called a node) is allocated space as it is added to the list.
    Every node in the list points to the next node in the list. Therefore, in a linked list, every node contains the following two types of information: \n
    \t 1. The value of the node or any other data that corresponds to tha node, and \n \t 2. A pointer or link to the nest node in the list.
    \n The last node in the list contains a NULL Pointer to indicate that it is the end or tail of the list. Since the memory for a node is dynamically allocated when it
    is added to the list. the total number of nodes that may be added to a list is limited only by the amount of memory available.</string>

<!--    Trees-->
    <string name="trees">🟣 <b>TREES</b></string>
    <string name="trees_description">A binary tree is a data structure which is defined a s a collection of elements called the nodes. Every node contains a left pointer,
    a right pointer, and a data element. Every binary tree has a root element pointed  b a root pointer. the root element is the topmost node in the tree. If root = Null,
    then the tree  is empty. \n \t Below figure shows a binary tree. If the root node R is not Null, then the two trees T1 and T2 are called the left and right subtrees of R.
    If T1 is non-empty , then t1 is said  to be the left successor of R. Likewise, if T2 is non-empty, then it is called  the right successor of R.</string>

<!--    graphs-->
     <string name="graphs">🟣 <b>GRAPHS</b></string>
    <string name="graphs_description">A graph is an abstract data structure that is used to implement the graph concept from mathematics. It is basically a collection of
    vertices (also called nodes) and edges that connect these vertices. A graph is often viewed as a generalization  of the tree structure, where instead of a having
    a purely parent-to-child relationship between tree nodes, any king of complex relationships between the nodes can be represented.</string>
</resources>